Katrina Rochelle Hicks

387 Troubadour Drive ◆ Sagamore Hills, OH 44067 ◆ (330) 348-1215 ◆ <u>KatrinaRHicks@Outlook.com</u>

https://github.com/Kathicks387

www.linkedin.com/in/katrinahicks387

OBJECTIVE

Seeking a position in which my years of experience in management and leadership may be utilized in the field of web design and development.

PROFILE

Beginning a new career in the field of web design and development, I eagerly await the opportunity to demonstrate the skills I have learned.

With my past experiences in management and leadership I am always willing to teach and be taught; lead and be led; to speak and to hear. Flexible and versatile – able to maintain a sense of calmness under pressure. Poised and competent with demonstrated ability to easily transcend cultural differences.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Lead Planner	MongoDB	Web, Server Side & 3rd Party APIs	Google Docs
HTML	Javascript	Microsoft PowerPoint	Google Slides
CSS	NodeJS	Microsoft Excel	Google Sheets
MYSQL	Express	Microsoft Word	Google Drive
Program Evaluator	Instructional Design	Microsoft Outlook	Gmail

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

STUDENT SUPPORT COORDINATOR

2019-2020

CLEVELAND HEIGHTS - UNIVERSITY HEIGHTS CITY SCHOOL DISTRICT

- Created Individual Educational Plans (IEP) for non-public school students.
- Held IEP meetings with parents.
- Responsible for inputting information in Education Management Information System (EMIS).
- Held meetings with non-public school district personnel.

PRINCIPAL GEARITY SCHOOL 2014-2019

CLEVELAND HEIGHTS - UNIVERSITY HEIGHTS CITY SCHOOL DISTRICT

- ◆ Led staff in implementing \$475,000.00 Ohio Straight-A DigiLit Grant.
- Worked with central office and John Carroll University staff to implement grant.
- Supervised and evaluated teaching and non-teaching staff.
- Maintained accurate balance of school budget by authorizing expenditures and requisitions.
- ◆ Led charge to change culture of school by creating Tiger Nation Friday and multiple other celebrations.
- Held yearly "Mock College Graduations" for all K-5 students to promote belief in students and parents that all students could obtain a college degree.
- Along with ELA Lead conducted trimester professional development for third grade teachers throughout the district
- ♦ Along with staff, worked diligently to obtain Ohio Stem School Designation.
- Worked with teaching staff to design and implement engaging lessons
- ◆ Introduced and implemented "Tynker" a coding program for first through sixth grade students
- ◆ Led monthly staff, weekly team and monthly union/administration meetings.

Katrina Rochelle Hicks

PRINCIPAL H. B. BOOKER SCHOOL 2010-2014 CLEVELAND METROPOLITAN SCHOOL DISTRICT

- ◆ Assisted in moving school from Academic Emergency to Academic Watch by increasing performance index score by 7.9 points.
- Created a safe and nurturing environment which decreased yearly serious incidents from 25 to 9.
- Supervised and evaluated 32 teaching staff and 21 non-teaching staff members.
- Created and inputted schedules for 547 students and 32 teaching staff members.
- Along with team, created the Academic Achievement Plan (AAP) for the 2010-2013 school years.
- Maintained accurate balance of school budget by authorizing expenditures and requisitions.
- ♦ Held monthly staff, team and union/administration meetings.

PRINCIPAL GRACEMOUNT SCHOOL 2003-2010 CLEVELAND METROPOLITAN SCHOOL DISTRICT

- Assisted in moving school from Academic Emergency to Effective during first year as principal.
- ♦ Was a change agent in reorganizing school from a K-5 building to a K-8 building.
- Managed and supervised 650 students and 38 teaching and 24 non-teaching staff members.
- Maintained accurate balance of school budget by authorizing expenditures and requisitions.
- ◆ Implemented the Conversation, Help, Activity, Movement, Participation, Successful Students Program (CHAMPS) for school prior to its adoption by the district.
- Along with the grant writing team, wrote and received MBNA, Ohio Reads and EETT Grants for school.
- ♦ Led the charge in successfully closing and ending the legacy of Gracemount School.
- ♦ Held monthly staff and union/administration meetings.

ASSISTANT PRINCIPAL GRACEMOUNT SCHOOL 2001-2003 CLEVELAND METROPOLITAN SCHOOL DISTRICT

- Assisted principal with the overall running of the building.
- Worked directly with fourth grade teachers to improve test scores.
- Responsible for buses, textbooks, recess and lunchroom operations.
- Immediate supervisor of fourth and fifth grade teachers and lunchroom and food service staff.

FAST SCHOOL PARTNER GRACEMOUNT & BOOKER SCHOOLS 2007-2012 CUYAHOGA COUNTY DRUG BOARD

- ♦ Worked with Cuyahoga County Drug Board to implement the Families and Schools Together research-based program at Gracemount and H. Barbara Booker Schools.
- ♦ Worked on a team with community, mental health and parent partners to put the eight-week program into action.
- Coached parents in the program on how to work with and communicate to their children.

TEACHER EMILE B. DESAUZE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL 1993-2001 CLEVELAND METROPOLITAN SCHOOL DISTRICT

- ♦ Instructed first and fourth grade students in English Language Arts, Mathematics, Science and Social Studies.
- Maintained accurate records of students' academics, behaviors and attendance.
- Communicated with parents through daily/weekly home to school folders.
- Served as grade level team leader for three years.
- Trained as TEEM (Teacher Enhancement of Elementary Mathematics) Leader for the school.

Katrina Rochelle Hicks

LEAD TEACHER/MANAGER

ENRICHMENT CENTER

1998-2001

EMILE B. DESAUZE/CLEVELAND METROPOLITAN SCHOOL DISTRICT

- Responsible for managing the Enrichment Center Before and After School Care Program.
- Planned lessons/activities and scheduled field trips.
- Processed and deposited payments and vouchers.
- Maintained TANF (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) records for the center.

EDUCATION

CASE WESTERN RESERVE UNIVERSITY – CODING BOOTCAMP

*Pass/Fail Course

JUNE 2020 TO Present

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN EDUCATIONAL ADMINISTRATION

CLEVELAND STATE UNIVERSITY

Dean's List 5 out of 6 semesters

JUNE 2001

◆ 3.26 GPA

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN ELEMENTARY EDUCATION CLEVELAND STATE UNIVERSITY JUNE 1993

♦ Dean's List 10 out of 12 quarters

♦ Cum Laude

◆ 3.54 GPA

REFERENCES

Karen Liddell-Anderson Director, Student Services 2155 Miramar Boulevard Cleveland Heights, Ohio 44118 (216) 371-7435 Work K Liddell@CHUH.org Charniece Holmes
Family Connections Coordinator
2843 Washington Boulevard
Cleveland Heights, Ohio 44118
(216) 321-0079 Work
(216) 773-5091 Cell
CHolmes@Familyconnections1.org

Rachael Coleman Principal, Roxboro Middle School 2400 Roxboro Road Cleveland Heights, Ohio 44106 (216) 320-3436 Work (216) 215-2526 Cell R Coleman@CHUH.org Tamica Marquis
Former School Parent
3598 Washington Boulevard
Cleveland Heights, Ohio 44118
(216) 324-6293
T.Liddell-Marquis@live.com

Toia Robinson Gifted & Title IX Coordinator 2155 Miramar Boulevard Cleveland Heights, Ohio 44118 (216) 320-2182 Work (614) 206-7263 Cell T Robinson@CHUH.org Heather Higham Gearity School Counselor 2323 Wrenford Road Cleveland Heights, Ohio 44118 (216) 320-4863 Work (440) 479-5216 Cell H Higham@CHUH.org